poetrysoup.com 2019-04-14

# Privacy Statement - PoetrySoup

PoetrySoup is committed to protecting your privacy and developing secure technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the PoetrySoup Web site and governs data collection and usage. By using the PoetrySoup website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

## PoetrySoup's Website Security Confirmed

PoetrySoup secures the personally identifiable information you provide on our website in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

The PoetrySoup website is secured by an SSL certificate from GeoTrust®. SSL certificates from GeoTrust® are the ultimate online security and trust solution delivering both 256-bit encryption and the True Site™ trust mark providing third-party website identity validation. The presence of SSL means you can rest assured that communications between your browser and this site's web servers are private and secure when the SSL session is activated.

## Collection of your Personal Information

PoetrySoup collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. PoetrySoup also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests, and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by PoetrySoup. This information can include your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by PoetrySoup for the operation of the service, to maintain the quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the PoetrySoup Web site.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through PoetrySoup public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: PoetrySoup does not read any of your private online communications.

PoetrySoup encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from PoetrySoup so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. PoetrySoup is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the PoetrySoup and PoetrySoup family of Web sites.

## Use of your Personal Information

PoetrySoup collects and uses your personal information to operate the PoetrySoup Web site and deliver the services you have requested. PoetrySoup also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from PoetrySoup and its affiliates. PoetrySoup may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

PoetrySoup does not sell, rent, or lease email addresses or telephone lists to third parties. PoetrySoup may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. Names and mailing addresses only (not email addresses) may be transferred to a third party. In addition, PoetrySoup may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to PoetrySoup, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

PoetrySoup does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

PoetrySoup keeps track of the Web sites and pages our customers visit within PoetrySoup, in order to determine what PoetrySoup services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within PoetrySoup to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

PoetrySoup Web sites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on PoetrySoup or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of PoetrySoup; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of PoetrySoup, or the public.

## Use of Cookies

The PoetrySoup Web site uses "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize PoetrySoup pages, or register with PoetrySoup site or services, a cookie helps PoetrySoup to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same PoetrySoup Web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the PoetrySoup features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the PoetrySoup services or Web sites you visit.

## Third Party Advertising

We use Google Adsense and other third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please [ _Click here_](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html) for Google ads. 

## Changes to this Statement

PoetrySoup will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. PoetrySoup encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how PoetrySoup is protecting your information.

## Contact Information

PoetrySoup welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that PoetrySoup has not adhered to this Statement, please [contact PoetrySoup](https://www.poetrysoup.com/contact_us.aspx). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.

## Cookie Declaration
